speech-writers.com 2011-12-31

# Privacy Statement

This privacy statement covers the site of www.speech-writers.com.   
Because it wants to demonstrate a commitment to users' privacy.

  * What personally identifiable information Speech-writers.com (and Speechwriters.com) collect. 
  * What personally identifiable information third parties collect through the web sites. 
  * What organization collects the information. 
  * How they uses the information. 
  * With whom they may share user information. 
  * What choices are available to users regarding collection, use and distribution of the information. 
  * What types of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under their control. 
  * How users can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, they should first contact Fred Crowe, Director, by email ([Click here to email Speech-Writers.com](http://www.speech-writers.com/contacts/)) or by phone +353 86 2531518.

## Information Collection and Use

### Information Collection

Speech-writers is the sole owner of the information collected on Speech-writers.com (and Speechwriters.com) other than credit card information which goes directly to our payment processing partner.

#### Order

We request information from the user on our order forms. A user must provide contact information (such as name, email, phone) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customer's orders. If we have trouble processing an order, the information is used only to contact the user.

#### Contact Us & Suggest-a-Speech

If you contact Speech-writers.com (and Speechwriters.com) through our [Contact Us](http://www.speech-writers.com/contacts/) form, we will collect contact information such as your name and email address. This information is used to respond to your question or request.

### Information Use

#### Cookies

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer tied to information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our sites. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. For the session ID cookie, once users close the browser, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user's hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions. We use a cookie to keep track of the products you are ordering. Some of our business partners use cookies on our sites (for example, affiliates).

#### Log Files

Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the sites, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. We use software called Wusage and Webtrends that uses log files to analyze user movement.

### Communications from the Sites

The only types of email communications that we send out are service related emails. These are information only emails and would normally include an opt-out option.

### Sharing

#### Legal Disclaimer

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web sites.

#### Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable)

We do not share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers.

#### Third Party Advertisers

We do not use any banner or other advertising on the sites.

#### Third Party Intermediaries

We use an outside company for credit card processing company to collect money from customer's credit cards. These companies do not automatically retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.

#### Service Providers

We use contract writers to write some material. In some cases the information that you provide for your personalized speech or poem will be passed to this third party. Each of these third parties has signed a contract and confidentiality clause. Your credit card information is not provided to these contractors. These third parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services.

#### Business Transitions

In the event Speech-writers.com (or Speechwriters.com) goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, users' personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. Users will be notified via email prior to a change of ownership or control of their personal information. If as a result of the business transition, the users' personally identifiable information will be used in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection they will be given choice consistent with our notification of changes section.

#### Disclosure

We post customer comments on our web site which may contain personally identifiable information such as the customer's name. We do obtain the customer's consent prior to posting the comment to post their name along with their comment.

We do not share Personally Identifiable Information for any unknown or unrelated uses. 

#### Links

This Web sites contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, Speech-writers.com (and Speechwriters.com), are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our sites and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by these web sites.

We do not share Personally Identifiable Information for any unknown or unrelated uses. 

### Security

This Web sites takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the Web sites, their information is protected both online and off-line.

When our order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when users are just 'surfing'. While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are in a secure environment, in a locked world class facility.

If users have any questions about the security at our Web sites, users can [click here to email Speech-Writers.com](http://www.speech-writers.com/contacts/)

### Supplementation of Information

We do not supplement the information we receive with information from 3rd party sources.

#### Purchasing History

We do not combine any information that we collect with any third party.

#### Enhancement of Marketing Profile

We do not purchase third party marketing data.

#### Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information

If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code, phone, email or postal address), or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users' personally identifiable information. This can usually be done by emailing our Customer Support [here](http://www.speech-writers.com/contacts/).

#### Notification of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users via email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. However, if users have opted out of all communication with the sites, or deleted/deactivated their account, then they will not be contacted, nor will their personal information be used in this new manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our Web sites notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post a notice we will also email users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.

#### Contact Information

If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at:

**Phone:** 1800 961 5617  
**Email:** [Click here to email Speech-Writers.com](http://www.speech-writers.com/contacts)  
**Postal Address:** 18 Vernon Rise. Clontarf, Dublin 3, Ireland. Europe.
